我是詹姆斯·提比略·柯克
My name is Captain James Tiberius Kirk
星际联邦的舰长
of the United Federation of Planets.
我谨以弗比安共和国的
I am appearing before you as a neutral representative
中立代表身份
of the Fibonan Republic.
传达我方的善意
I bring you a message of goodwill
并为在场尊贵的提纳奇代表团
and present to you esteemed members of the Teenaxi Delegation,
献上来自弗比安最高议会的礼物 以示最诚挚的敬意
a gift from the Fibonan High Council with the highest regard.
那个东西有问题吗？
What's wrong with it?
什么意思？
Uh, excuse me?
他们为什么不想要了？
Why don't they want it anymore?
呃 就是 它曾是古代兵器
Uh, well, this was once a piece of an ancient weapon,
现在则是
and now they offer it as a symbol of...
和平的象征
Of peace.
对弗比安人来说
In the Fibonan culture,
呈上武器代表休兵
to surrender a weapon is an offer of truce.
他们怎么得到这东西的？
How did they come by it?
他们很早之前就有了
They told me they acquired it a long time ago.
所以是偷来的
So they stole it, then.
不是的
No, they, um... Well, I don't know.
我们比你了解弗比安人
You don't know the Fibonans like we do!
没错 阁下 这份礼物
Yeah, that's very true. Your Excellency, this gift...
他们是一群不值得信任的小偷
They're a crowd of untrustworthy thieves
恨不得我们死在自家里
who want to see us murdered in our own beds!
这个珍贵的文物是信任与和平的象征
This beloved artifact is a symbol of trust and peace.
他们想把我们碎尸万段 放在火上烤
They want to chop us into pieces and roast us over a fire!
不是这样的
No, no... I don't think that's true.
然后把我们吃掉
And eat us!
什么？
What?
斯科特 把我传送回去
Scotty! Get me out of here!
- 这么快 - 斯科特
- That was quick. - Scotty!
地表有不少干扰
There's quite a bit of surface interference, sir.
斯科特
Scotty!
滚开
Get it off of me!
我的制服又破了
I ripped my shirt again.
进展还顺利吗？
How'd it go?
舰长 提纳奇人愿意签条约了吗？
Captain, did you manage to broker a treaty with the Teenaxi?
呃 就差那么一步
Uh... Let's just say I came up short.
你能不能 呃
Will you, uh,
帮我归档然后放回保管室 史巴克？谢了
log that and put it in the vault, Spock? Thank you.
吉姆 你气色糟透了
Jim, you look like crap.
谢谢你 老骨头
Thank you, Bones.
你的太阳穴又爆青筋了 没事吧？
You got that little vein popping out of your temple again. You okay?
好到不行 今天跟平常没两样
Never better! Just another day in the fleet.
舰长日志 星历2263.2
Captain's Log, Stardate 2263.2.
今天是进行太空任务的第966天
Today is our 966th day in deep space,
五年任务过了也快三年
a little under three years into our five-year mission.
在外层空间待愈久
The more time we spend out here,
愈搞不清楚今天会什么时候结束
the harder it is to tell where one day ends
明天又会什么时候开始
and the next one begins.
要脚踏实地过日子很难 因为连重力都是人造的
It can be a challenge to feel grounded when even gravity is artificial.
但我们尽可能让星舰像在家一样自在
But, well, we do what we can to make it feel like home.
舰员们一如往常表现优异
The crew, as always, continues to act admirably
虽然他们必须在外层空间度过漫漫长日
despite the rigors of our extended stay here in outer space.
并做出个人牺牲
And the personal sacrifices they have made.
我们持续搜寻新的物种
We continue to search for new life forms
以建立稳固邦交
in order to establish firm diplomatic ties.
我们在未知领域长期探索
Our extended time in uncharted territory
让机械设备承受极大负担
has stretched the ship's mechanical capacities.
幸亏轮机室有
But fortunately our engineering department,
斯科特坐镇 让问题迎刃而解
led by Mr. Scott, is more than up to the job.
除了船本身 长时间的共处
The ship aside, prolonged cohabitation has
也对舰员之间的关系产生了影响
definitely had effects on interpersonal dynamics.
有的经验很美好
Some experiences for the better,
有的下场凄惨
and some for the worse.
对我来说 这一切开始变得好像难以捉摸
As for me, things have started to feel a little episodic.
我们航行得愈远 我就愈怀疑
The farther out we go, the more I find myself wondering
这么做的目的到底是什么
what it is we're trying to accomplish.
如果宇宙无穷无尽
If the universe is truly endless,
我们是否永远追寻不到我们的目标？
then are we not striving for something forever out of reach?
企业号预计在联邦最先进的新基地
The Enterprise is scheduled for a reprovisioning stop at Yorktown,
约克镇做短暂停留并进行补给
the Federation's newest and most advanced starbase.
或许短暂的休息能让我们
Perhaps a break from routine will offer up some respite
暂时脱离未知的神秘
from the mysteries of the unknown.
(上传至星际联邦数据库)
对不起 我来迟了
Sorry I'm late.
昆塞尔因为感冒在流某种 强酸性的绿色黏液
Keenser's leaking some kind of highly acidic green goo,
而斯科特 很怕他的鼻涕会喷到 曲速核上
and Scotty's terrified he's gonna sneeze on the warp core
那会要了我们的命
and kill us all.
你在喝什么？
What the hell are you drinking?
就是上次在色索斯拿到的
Uh, I'm pretty sure it's the rest of that Saurian brandy
萨乌里白兰地
we picked up on Thasus.
老天 你想喝瞎掉吗？
My God, man, are you trying to go blind?
这酒是非法的
That stuff's illegal.
再说
Besides,
我在契科夫的柜子里找到好东西
I found this in Chekov's locker.
- 哇 - 厉害吧？
- Wow. - Right?
我就知道他爱喝伏特加
I mean, I always assumed he'd be
- 没错 - 喝伏特加的好手 一点儿没错
- a vodka man. - A vodka guy, exactly.
我想好好庆祝你的生日
I wanted to have something appropriate for your birthday.
呃 还有几天才到 你知道我不在乎
Uh, that's in a couple days. You know I don't care about that.
我知道 你不喜欢在生日当天庆祝
I know. I know you don't like celebrating it on the day
因为同一天也是你爸的忌日
because it's also the day your pa bit the dust.
我的神经还算敏感
I was being sensitive.
医学院没教你要有礼貌？
Did they teach you about bedside manner in medical school?
你们南部人就是这样
It's just your southern charm.
- 哦 真不是盖的 - 哦
- Oh, yeah. That's good. - Ooh.
超棒
Lordy!
你会打给你妈吗？
Are you gonna call your mom?
当然 我当天再打
Yeah, of course. I'll call her on the day.
我又老一岁了
I'm one year older.
这是很自然的事
Yep, that's usually how it works.
他永远也到不了我这个年纪了
A year older than he ever got to be.
他加入星际舰队是因为
He joined Starfleet because he...
认同它的理念
He believed in it.
而我是为了争一口气
I joined on a dare.
你加入是想知道够不够格当他儿子
You joined to see if you could live up to him.
你一直以来都以父亲为榜样
Uh, you spent all this time trying to be George Kirk
现在却思考该怎么做自己
and now you're wondering just what it means to be Jim.
为什么在这里
Why you're out here.
敬你完好的视力 还有浓密的头发
To perfect eyesight and a full head of hair.
我是柯克
Kirk here.
舰长 约克镇基地快到了
Captain, approaching Yorktown base.
我马上过去 苏鲁
I'm on my way, Mr. Sulu.
我生日这件事别告诉任何人
Let's keep this birthday thing under wraps, huh?
安啦 我可是敏感先生
Yeah, you know me. Mr. Sensitive.
哇 好惊人
Wow. That is impressive.
是啊 很美吧？
Aye, she's a beauty, isn't she?
这颗大球难看死了
What a damn monstrosity!
难道不能租个星球当基地吗？
Couldn't we just rent some space on a planet?
联邦若偏好某个星球的地理位置
Showing geographical favoritism among inducted Federation worlds
可能导致外交情势紧张
could cause diplomatic tension.
这样就不紧张？
Oh, you don't think that looks tense?
看起来就像一颗 随时会破掉的玻璃球
Looks like a damn snow globe in space just waiting to break!
你老是嘴巴不饶人 老骨头
Oh, that's the spirit, Bones.
(公共传送器)
史巴克
Spock!
有时间谈谈吗？
Do you have a moment?
当然 娜尤塔
Of course, Nyota.
这个应该还你
I think you should have this back.
毕竟是你母亲的遗物
After all, it belonged to your mother.
我们瓦肯人不习惯
It's not in the Vulcan custom
把送出去的礼物再收回来
to receive again that which was given as a gift.
你们分手啦？
You guys break up?
你干了啥好事？
What'd you do?
一个典型的抽象提问 医生
A typically reductive inquiry, Doctor.
史巴克 你要知道
You know, Spock,
如果一个地球女说"错在我 不在你"
if an Earth girl says, uh, "It's me, not you,"
那么错的一定是你
it's definitely you.
不好意思 史巴克中校
Excuse me. Commander Spock?
可以占用您一点时间吗？
May we have a moment of your time?
太棒了 我从没来过这里
This is wonderful! You know I've never been here?
听说这边的酒吧很赞
What I hear is that the bars here are excellent.
真高兴你们能来
I'm so glad you guys could come.
谢谢你们告知我这个消息
Thank you for bringing this to my attention.
生生不息 繁荣昌盛
Live long and prosper.
(史巴克大使 联邦大使  联邦星舰企业号-二副 联邦星舰企业号A-大副)
(星际联邦)
有一艘来路不明的船舰
IFF alert on incoming vessel.
来源不明 非联邦型号
Unidentified. Non-Federation.
身分不明船舰请注意 你无权接近
Attention, unidentified vessel. You are not authorized for approach.
关闭引擎并等待进一步指示
Power down and await instructions.
身分不明船舰 请遵守规定
Unidentified vessel, please comply.
正常说话即可
Speak normally.
语言分析完成
Language analysis complete.
这样可以吗？
Is this working?
我们在星云里进行科学任务
We were on a science mission inside the nebula.
我们的船突然失灵
Our ship suffered a critical malfunction.
我躲进了逃生舱
I took an escape pod
接着船便坠毁在附近星球
before the ship crash landed on a nearby planet.
我们需要一艘能在星云里航行的船
We need a ship capable of navigating the nebula.
你们之中一定有人
You must have someone
可以帮助我们
who can help us.
我们追踪了他们受困于 未知星云里的船
We tracked her stranded ship to a sector of uncharted nebula,
位于210标14
here at 2-1-0 mark 14.
- 进行过长程扫描吗？- 没有数据
- Uh, long-range scan? - No data.
星云密度太高了 那是一块未知区域
The nebula is too dense. It's uncharted space.
企业号拥有舰队最佳的 导航系统
Well, the Enterprise does have the best navigational system in the fleet.
绝对可以胜任
She could handle it.
这里唯一具备更先进科技的星舰
The only ship here with more advanced technology
还在建造当中
is still under construction.
但我看重的不只是船本身
But it's not just the ship that I'm sending.
- 我去召集舰员 - 舰长
- I'll gather the crew. - Captain.
我从星舰司令部收到你的申请表
Starfleet command sent me your application
看来你想争取基地的中将职位
for the Vice Admiral position here at this installation.
是的 长官 呃
Yes, ma'am. Um...
可以的话 我想
If I may, I would
推荐史巴克中校代替我 成为企业号舰长
recommend Commander Spock replace me as Captain of the Enterprise.
他是星舰军官的典范 一定会是优秀舰长
He is an exemplary Starfleet officer. He'd make a great captain.
你知道 这不是什么稀奇的事
It isn't uncommon, you know,
就算是舰长
even for a captain,
也会有想离开的时候
to want to leave.
在浩瀚无垠的太空中 没有相对的方向
There is no relative direction in the vastness of space.
只有你自己
There is only yourself,
还有你的星舰和舰员
your ship, your crew.
迷失比想象中容易
It's easier than you think, to get lost.
- 不是因为 - 这件事我会上呈到总议会
- It's not about... - I'll bring it up with the General Council.
等你回来再讨论
We'll discuss it when you return.
谢谢
Ma'am.
- 史巴克 - 舰长
- Mr. Spock. - Captain.
- 我在想 - 或许
- I was thinking... - Perhaps there...
- 不 你讲吧 - 舰长 你先
- No, please. - Captain, after you.
我坚持
I insist.
这次任务结束后 我们应该坐下来谈谈
After this mission, we should, uh, sit down.
有件事我想跟你讨论
There's something I need to talk to you about.
我也有事想说
I as well have something to share.
我们合作无间 对吧？
We make a good team. Right?
我是这么认为
I believe we do.
我坚持
I insist.
乌胡拉上尉 开启全舰广播
Lieutenant Uhura, open a ship-wide channel.
好的 舰长
Yes, Captain.
企业号舰员注意
Attention, crew of the Enterprise.
我们下一个任务是
Our mission is straightforward.
拯救一艘受困于未知星球上的船
Rescue a crew stranded on a planet in uncharted space.
我们将进入一个不稳定的星云
Our trajectory will take us through an unstable nebula,
失去与星际舰队的所有联系
one which will disable all communications with Starfleet.
一切都得靠自己
We're gonna be on our own.
企业号拥有其他星舰没有的优势
The Enterprise has something no other ship in the fleet has,
那就是各位
you.
我们都很清楚
And as we've come to understand,
所谓的未知并不存在
there is no such thing as the unknown,
它们只是暂时隐藏起来
only the temporarily hidden.
通话完毕
Kirk out.
嗯 数据显示星云密度正在减少
Mmm. Readings indicate cloud density diminishing, sir.
这是阿塔密德星 我的船就是困在这里
This is Altamid. My ship is stranded here.
即将抵达M级行星 阿塔密德
Approaching Altamid. Class-M planet.
地下有巨大建设
Massive subterranean development.
但地表没有物种
But limited to no life forms on the surface.
近距离警报 长官
Proximity alert, sir!
有不明船舰朝我们过来
We have an unknown ship heading right for us.
- 乌胡拉上尉 呼叫对方 - 好的 舰长
- Lieutenant Uhura, hail them. - Yes, Captain.
无回应 我发现某种讯号
No response. I am picking up some kind of signal.
他们在干扰电波
They're jamming us.
把影像放大 苏鲁
Magnify, Mr. Sulu.
这是什么？
What is this?
开启防护罩 红色警戒
Shields up! Red alert!
随意开火
Fire at will.
我们的光炮伤不了敌人
Sir, our phasers are having minimal effect
鱼雷也追踪不了目标
and our torpedos can't track their movements!
火力全开
Fire everything we've got.
舰长 我们的装备不足以交战
Captain, we are not equipped for this manner of engagement.
防护罩频率没有用
Shield frequencies have no effect, sir!
偏导碟毁了 防护罩失灵
They took out the dish! Shields are inoperable!
- 启动曲速引擎 苏鲁 - 知道了
- Warp us out of here, Mr. Sulu. - Yes, sir.
怎么没反应？
Why the hell aren't we moving?
无法启动曲速引擎
I can't engage the warp drive, sir!
斯科特 让曲速引擎运作
Scotty, I need warp now!
不行啊 长官 因为引擎舱
I cannae, sir! The nacelles, they've...
不见了
They've gone!
安全人员 启动所有紧急程序
Security, engage all emergency procedures.
启动28号协定1A0警报
Active protocol 28 Code One Alpha Zero.
所有人员就警戒位置
All personnel to alert stations.
长官 第12至15层舰身遭到破坏
Sir, I have hull breaches in levels 12 to 15,
还有第6 9 31和21层
6, 9, 31 and 21, sir.
舰长 我可能可以把备用能源
Captain! There's a chance I can reroute the energy reserves
从曲速核转移至脉冲引擎
from the warp core to the impulse engines.
回到星云里 搞不好可以甩掉他们
If we can get back into the nebula, maybe we could lose them.
尽你所能 斯科特
Do whatever you have to, Scotty.
小矮子
Wee man!
我们走
Let's go.
搞定了 克劳
接上等离子导管 等我一声令下就移转 等离子
Fit the plasma conduits and stand by to reroute on my mark!
亚布罗讷到手了
攻下这艘船
- 舰长 - 请说
- Captain. - Go, Spock.
我找到了这场攻击行动的敌方领袖
I have identified the individual who appears to be leading the attack party.
他潜入保管室
He infiltrated the archive vault
拿走了提纳奇的文物
and removed the artifact from our mission on Teenax.
保持距离直到
Hold your distance until...
史巴克
Spock!
- 你们两个跟我来 苏鲁 接手指挥 - 遵命 长官
- You two, with me. Sulu, you have the conn. - Yes, sir.
我的天啊
My God.
(状态危急)
这是怎么回事？
What the hell?
医生？
Doctor?
我们必须马上撤离
Doctor, we must evacuate now!
柯克
Captain
舰长
Kirk.
太好了 脉冲引擎能量全满
Yes! We are at 100% impulse.
干得好 斯科特
Great work, Mr. Scott!
全速冲往星云
Maximum impulse towards the nebula.
好的
Aye.
克劳  船掉头了
切断它的喉咙
柯克呼叫舰桥
Kirk to Bridge.
我们失去了惯性阻尼器
We are losing the inertial dampeners!
全舰系统正在失灵 舰长
Systems are failing ship-wide, Captain.
紧急闸门关闭中
Emergency bulkheads are sealing,
但结构完整性剩18% 而且不断往下掉
but structural integrity is at 18% and falling, sir!
弃船逃生 苏鲁
Abandon ship, Mr. Sulu.
启动警报
Sound the alarm.
所有人员弃船逃生
Abandon ship. All personnel.
逃生舱要有机会逃出
We need to give those pods a chance to escape.
你能把敌船引开吗？
Can you lead those ships away?
脉冲引擎仍试着从曲速储备取得能量
Impulse engines are still trying to draw power from the warp reserve.
要等到碟形母舰分离之后才能动
We cannot move until the saucer is separated.
我来处理
I'll handle it.
好的 长官
Aye-aye, sir.
弃船逃生 所有人员立即撤离
Abandon ship. All personnel evacuate immediately.
你没事吧 天啊 把他扶起来
You okay? Oh, my God. Get him up. Help him up.
扶好你了
Got you.
快点去逃生舱
We've got to get you guys to an escape pod. Go.
动作快 丝尔少尉
Go! Ensign Syl.
我需要你帮忙
I need your help.
好的 长官
Yes, sir.
我的天啊
My God.
史巴克 他们把舰员都抓走了
Spock, they're taking the crew!
弃船逃生 所有人员 立即撤离
Abandon ship. All personnel evacuate immediately.
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
碟形母舰怎么还没分离？
The saucer should be free by now!
我知道 苏鲁 舰长应该在那里才对
I know, Mr. Sulu. The Captain should be there!
所有人员立即撤离
All personnel evacuate immediately.
(碟形母舰分离  请确认)
脉冲引擎正在从辅助发电机取得能量
Impulse engines drawing power from auxiliary generators.
舰长
Captain!
还有多少人员在碟形母舰上？
How many of the crew are still aboard the saucer?
没人了
None.
如果我没有看错读数
But if I'm reading this correctly,
那些入侵者带走了他们
the intruders are taking them.
舰长 我们被这个星球的重力拉住了
Captain, we are caught in the planet's gravity.
无法离开
We cannot pull away.
快去逃生舱
Get to your Kelvin Pods.
- 遵命 - 好的 舰长
- Yes, sir. - Aye, Captain.
大家快走
Come on, let's go!
我们走
Let's go.
快
Come on.
契科夫
Chekov!
你早就知道我们会被攻击
You knew. You knew we'd be attacked.
你不了解
You don't understand.
舰长 柯克舰长
Captain! Captain Kirk!
对 我说了谎
Yes. I lied.
我们的船遭到攻击
Our ship was attacked.
契科夫 寻找生还者的踪迹
Chekov, check the comms for survivors.
- 好的 舰长 - 他是谁？
- Aye, Captain. - Who is he?
他叫克劳
His name is Krall.
他带走了我的舰员 跟你的情况一样
He took my crew. Like he took yours.
他为什么对企业号了如指掌？
How did he know so much about the Enterprise?
我只知道如果照他的意思做
All I know is that if I did this,
他就会释放我的舰员
he would set them free.
契科夫 扫描仪有任何发现吗？
Chekov, are you picking anything up on those scanners?
什么都没有
Nothing, sir.
- 他们会不会 - 不会的
- What if they... - No, no.
他们只是被带走
He was taking them.
我们必须找到碟形母舰
We have to find that saucer.
上面的扫描系统范围比三度仪大
Even minimal scanning systems will have more range than a tricorder.
是的 舰长 你说得没错
Aye, Captain, it's possible.
舰长
Captain.
我这么做是为了保护舰员
I was protecting my crew.
我们正在找舰长
你叫什么名字？
What is your name?
你怎么会说我们的语言？
How do you know our language?
我了解人类
I know your kind.
我是联邦星舰企业号的 娜尤塔·乌胡拉上尉
I am Lieutenant Nyota Uhura of the U.S.S. Enterprise.
你引发战争的行径已经触犯
And you have committed an act of war against the...
星际联邦
Federation!
星际联邦专门引发战争
Federation is an act of war.
是你攻击我们
You attacked us.
你们的舰长
Your captain...
你为什么为他牺牲？
Why did you sacrifice yourself for him?
他也会做同样的事
He would have done the same.
如果他活下来 一定会来救我们
And if he made it off of that ship, he will come for us.
正合我意 乌胡拉上尉
I am counting on it, Lieutenant Uhura.
真是有够衰
I can't believe it.
天哪 史巴克
My God, Spock.
天啊
God...
在这坐着
Sit down over here.
很好 坐下 慢慢来
Okay. Okay, sit. Easy.
好
Okay.
尽量放轻松 你不会有事
Now, just try and relax. You're gonna be okay.
你的声音透出勉强的乐观
The forced optimism in your voice suggests
显示你试着以冷静态度处理
that you are trying to elicit a sense of calm in order to...
那就不用马粪哄你了
I'll cut the horseshit.
我看不出来排泄物
Doctor, I fail to see how excrement of any kind
与我们的当前状况有任何关联
bears relevance on our current situation.
哇 哇 你想干嘛？
Whoa, whoa, what the hell are you doing?
我们必须离开 医生
We must keep moving, Doctor.
这玩意儿穿进了你的腹部
Spock, this thing's punctured your iliac region!
时间宝贵
Time is a critical factor.
我就是这个意思
That's exactly what I'm trying to tell you.
东西不取出来 你会死
Look, if I can't take this out, you're gonna die.
东西取出来但血流不止 你也会死
Okay? If I take it out and can't stop the bleeding, you're gonna die.
两个选项都不吸引人
I can see no appeal in either option.
相信我 我也是这么想
Believe it or not, neither can I.
那么
So,
如果我记得没错
if I remember correctly,
瓦肯人
the Vulcans
心脏长在人类肝脏的地方
have their hearts where humans have their livers.
没错 医生
That is correct, Doctor.
这样就说得通了
That explains a thing or two.
你很走运 如果伤口再往左移个一吋
You know, you're lucky. An inch to the left...
你早就死了
And you'd be dead already.
我实在不懂 史巴克
I just don't get it, Spock.
他们干嘛攻击我们？
I mean, what did they attack us for?
就是为了小不点们
I mean, they do all this for some
都不要的那个玩意儿吗？
doodad that the tiny critters didn't want?
把不了解的事过度简化
It is unwise to trivialize
并非明智之举 医生
that which one simply does not understand, Doctor.
我们只能假设它不只是个"玩意儿"
We can safely assume it is more important than a doodad.
你知道你刚刚侮辱了我两次吗？
I think you just managed to insult me twice, Spock.
行了
Okay.
史巴克 我只有一个问题
All right, Spock, I just got one question.
- 你最喜欢什么颜色？- 我看不出关联
- What's your favorite color? - I fail to see the relevance.
我听说出其不意比较不痛
Yeah. They say it hurts less if it's a surprise.
套用一句你熟悉的说法
If I may adopt a parlance with which you are familiar,
我可以肯定这个理论 马粪
I can confirm your theory to be horseshit.
我们必须离开这里
We got to get out of here.
走吧
Come on.
开什么玩笑？
You're kidding me, aren't you?
你们好
Hello there.
我叫蒙哥马利·斯科特
My name is Montgomery Scott. And, uh,
请问你们是？
who might you be?
看着点 小子
Watch it, sonny.
我发起狠来也不是好惹的
I'm pretty handy when I want to be, all right?
别再过来
Don't come back!
他们知道我们的厉害了
We certainly showed them, eh, lassie?
那是星舰的东西 你不可以拿
That's Starfleet property, okay. You cannae just take it.
但我今天特别大方 你要拿就拿
Uh, but I'm feeling generous today, so have at it.
那是哪里来的？
Where you get that?
- 你会讲英文？- 我在家学的
- Is that English? - I learn it from my house.
- 哪里来的？- 这是我的星舰徽章
- Where you get that? - It's my Starfleet insignia.
它代表什么？
What does it mean?
代表我是星舰军官 轮机组
Means that I'm an officer of Starfleet. Uh, engineering division.
- 轮机？- 对 修东西的
- Engineering? - That's right. I fix things.
我知道什么是轮机
I know what is engineering.
你跟毁了我的船的那帮混蛋 不是一伙的吧？
You're not with those bastards that killed my ship, are you?
看来应该不是
I'll take that as a no.
那个人叫克劳 他跟他的
He is Krall. Him and his
蜜蜂们
bees.
他们在各个星球寻找死亡机器
They search the stars for a death machine.
所以你才会来到这里 我们才会都在这里
They're the reason why you here. Why we are all here.
那三个恶煞也是？
Even those three scunners?
他们从天空掉下来 跟你我一样
They have fallen from the sky, like me and you.
跟我来 快
Come with me. Now!
等一下 小姑娘 我今天过得很凄惨
Wait, no... Hang on a minute, lassie. I'm having a difficult day here.
我还得找到我的舰员
I've got to find my crewmates.
我会帮你找到你的舰员
I will help you find your mates.
然后你要帮我
And then you will help me.
帮你什么？
With what?
你要我修东西？
You want me to fix something?
对 你帮我 我也帮你
Yes. You help me, and I help you.
以目前情况看来
All right, well, things being as they are,
我也没有更好的选择 带路吧
I doubt I'll get a better offer today, so, lead the way.
很好
Good.
我叫洁拉
I am Jaylah.
- 你是蒙哥马利·斯科特 - 对 斯科特
- And you are Montgomery Scott. - Aye, Scotty.
跟我来 蒙哥马利·斯科特
Come now, Montgomery Scotty.
好 等等我
All right, hold up.
是企业号
The Enterprise.
她可能 连舰桥的电力都无法供给 舰长
She may not even have power to the Bridge, Captain.
她一定还能做些什么
She still has a few tricks up her sleeve.
我相信她可以的
I'd bet on it.
麦考伊呼叫企业号 请回答
McCoy to Enterprise. Come in.
麦考伊呼叫企业号
McCoy to Enterprise.
慢慢来 史巴克
Hey, take it easy there, Spock.
你的伤口只是暂时缝合
That was just a temporary fix back there.
我知道 医生
I understand, Doctor.
美得惊人
Fascinating.
不祥 黑暗 危险
Ominous. Dark. Dangerous.
所以我们要进去？
We're going in.
这些符号 在攻击中被夺走的
Intriguing. These symbols are the same as those
文物上也有这些符号
depicted on the artifact taken in the attack.
你觉得它来自这里？
You think it came from here?
看起来是如此
It would seem so.
见鬼 史巴克
Damn it, Spock.
放轻松
Easy. Easy.
快点
Hurry.
- 到了没？- 别问个不停
- Are we there yet? - Stop asking that.
- 对不起 - 这边 来
- Sorry. - This is the way. Come.
注意脚下 别踩到我设的陷阱
And watch your steps. You do not want to set off my traps.
很聪明嘛
That's clever.
这是什么地方？
What is this place?
- 我的房子 - 你的房子？
- This is my house. - Your house?
慢着 难道这是一艘船？
Hold on a minute. Is this a ship?
我帮你找朋友 你帮我修好它
I help you find your friends and you help me fix it.
我就可以永远离开这个星球
So I can leave this planet forever.
等一下 这是你的船？
Wait a minute. Is this your ship?
不 蒙哥马利·斯科特
No, Montgomery Scotty.
是你们的
It's yours.
哦 天哪
Oh, my good Lord.
(联邦星舰富兰克林号)
(舰籍编号NX326)
舰长 看来还有电力
Captain, it looks like there is power.
好 我们去舰桥才能找其他舰员的位置
All right, let's get to the Bridge and find the crew.
控制台没有损坏
The console is intact, Captain.
我会试着接上电力
I will try to reroute power to it.
动作快
Work fast.
这里一亮会引来很多注意
Once we get this place lit up, we're gonna draw a lot of attention.
你能找到他们吗？
What do you think, can you find them?
可以 舰长
Aye, Captain.
我正在重新配置扫描仪
I am reconfiguring scanners
把目标设定成舰员的讯号
to modulate for the crew's signals.
你跟我来 我藏了个东西
You're with me. I left something behind.
你的感冒还真严重
That is one heck of a cold.
干得好 昆塞尔
Nice job, Keenser.
好了 下一轮守卫还有15分钟才会来 我们走
All right, we got about 15 minutes until the next guard rotation. Come on.
走吧 快
Let's go. Come on.
这边
Come on.
这是麦哲伦号探测器
This is the Magellan Probe.
联邦曾用它在星云里找路
The Federation was using these to find a way through the nebula.
克劳拿它做什么？
What's he using it for?
有什么发现？
What do you see?
他在探测器之间架设了亚空间通讯链接
He's been piggybacking the subspace links between the probes.
我们能用它来发求救讯号吗？
Can we use it to send a distress signal?
我可以试试看
I can try.
送出去了
It's sent.
他能进入约克镇的数据库
He's accessed the Yorktown database.
什么
What?
他有星舰数据文件 日志
He's got Starfleet data files, ship logs,
包括企业号的
including the Enterprise.
他一直看着我们的一举一动
He's been watching us this whole time.
舰长
Captain,
那个武器一直都在这艘船上吗？
the artifact was on the ship the whole time?
带在身上太危险 所以我藏在这里
I couldn't afford to get caught with it, so I hid it in here.
告诉克劳我找到亚布罗讷了
Tell Krall I have the Abronath.
每个悲惨故事你都相信吗？
Do you believe every sad story you hear?
看情况
Not every.
放下光炮
Put the phaser down.
请照做
Please.
追踪到了吧 契科夫？
You get it, Chekov?
是的 舰长 我查到了收话者的位置
Aye, Captain, I have traced the location of her call.
克劳要这个东西做什么？
What does Krall want with this thing?
把你们从自我
To save you
解救出来
from yourselves.
舰长
Captain!
- 还好吧？- 没事 舰长
- You all right? - Aye, Captain,
但我们被困住了
but we are trapped!
你能启动它吗？
Can you get this thing started?
你的意思是要使用推进器吗？
Are you intimating that we should engage the thrusters?
不然你有别的建议吗？
I am open to other suggestions.
好吧
Okay.
- 有个问题 - 什么？
- There is a problem. - What?
里头有燃料但我无法让它燃烧
The fuel is primed, but I cannot get it to combust.
舰长 我们可说是 站在一颗超大炸弹上
Oy, Captain, we are basically standing on a very large bomb.
如果你没打中压缩器
If you miss the combustion compressor...
我会打中
I'm not gonna miss, come on.
你知道它长什么样子吗？
Do you even know what the combustion compressor looks like?
方方的 对吧？
It's square, right?
不 是圆圆的
No, sir, it's round.
我刚刚就是这么说
That's what I said.
快跑
Run!
走
Go!
契科夫
Chekov!
契科夫 快跑
Chekov! Move!
你们自以为知道
You think you know
牺牲的意义是什么？
what sacrifice really means?
星际联邦告诉你们 冲突不应该存在
Federation has taught you that conflict should not exist.
但没有了抗争
But without struggle,
你永远找不到真实的自我
you would never know who you truly are.
你根本不了解我们
You have no idea who we are.
但很快就能见真章
But you'll soon find out.
你说你们刚才传送出去的求救讯号？
You mean the distress signal you thought you sent?
我帮你们改了坐标
The coordinates were altered.
你们的救难舰会被困在星云里
Your rescue ships will be stranded in the nebula
基地变得不堪一击
and your base left vulnerable.
你打算攻击约克镇
You're going to attack Yorktown.
数百万来自星联各盟邦的人齐聚一堂
Millions of souls from every Federation world holding hands.
这目标再完美不过
It's a perfect target.
你错了 团结会带来力量
You're wrong. There is strength in unity.
他人的力量 上尉
The strength of others, Lieutenant,
是我生命的泉源
is what has kept me alive.
不可以
No!
史巴克
Spock.
史巴克 醒醒啊 该死
Spock, wake up, damn it!
我的意识完全清醒 医生
I am entirely conscious, Doctor.
我只是在思考死亡的本质
I'm simply contemplating the nature of mortality.
开始在想人生哲理了？
Feeling philosophical, huh?
这就是大量失血的后遗症
Massive blood loss will do that to you.
你问我为什么和乌胡拉上尉分道扬镳
You asked me why Lieutenant Uhura and I parted ways.
瓦肯星灭亡之后 我开始认为
I became concerned, in the light of Vulcan's demise,
我对我的种族有一份责任
that I owed a debt of duty to my species.
你觉得你应该生瓦肯宝宝是吧？
You thought you should be off making little Vulcans, huh?
这就是了 难怪她会不开心
Yeah, I can see how that would upset her.
我原本打算进一步跟她谈谈
I intended to discuss it with her further,
但我收到了令我措手不及的消息
but I received some news which affected me unexpectedly.
什么消息？
What news?
史巴克大使过世了
Ambassador Spock has died.
史巴克 我很遗憾
Spock, I'm so sorry.
我无法想象那是什么感觉
I can't imagine what that must feel like.
如果你像他活了那么多辈子
When you've lived as many lives as he,
惧怕死亡是没有道理的
fear of death is illogical.
惧怕死亡
Fear of death
是让我们活下来的动力
is what keeps us alive.
我想过和他一样的人生
I want to live as he did.
因此我决定
That is why I decided
转移我的目标并延续他的遗志
to redirect my efforts and continue his work
在新瓦肯耕耘
on New Vulcan.
你要离开星舰？
You're leaving Starfleet?
吉姆怎么说？
What did Jim have to say about that?
我尚未找到时机告诉他
I could not find the time to tell him.
我敢说他一定会大受打击
Well, I can tell you he's not gonna like that.
我不知道他没有你该怎么办
Hell, I don't know what he'd do without you.
反观我是会开派对庆祝啦
I mean, me on the other hand, I'd throw a party, but...
天哪 你精神错乱了
My God, you're getting delirious.
我们距离收话者的坐标还有多远？
How far are we from the coordinates of that call?
还有一段距离
Still a ways, sir.
- 舰长？- 何事？
- Captain? - Yeah.
你是从什么时候开始怀疑她的？
When did you begin to suspect her?
还不够早
Not soon enough.
你怎么发现的？
How did you know?
我想说
Well...
可能是因为我很容易察觉到危险吧
I guess you could say I've got a good nose for danger.
快跑
Run!
那是音乐吗？
Is that music?
这是哪里来的音乐？
Where on earth is that coming from?
那边
There.
我把那个小盒子插上电源后
I plugged the little box in the power cell
它的小嘴巴就开始唱歌
and the little mouths make it sing.
很聪明嘛
That's very clever.
这音乐对我来说有点老派
Music's a bit old-fashioned for my taste,
很吵又令人分心
not to mention very loud and distracting,
不过 还真不错
but, aye, well played.
我喜欢它的节拍和吼叫
I like the beats and shouting.
是吗？
Oh, you do?
- 关掉 - 不用啦
- Switch it off. - Ach, you're okay.
关掉
Switch it off!
有人踩到了我的陷阱
Someone set off one of my traps.
舰长？
Captain?
- 你认识这些人？- 是的 小姑娘
- You know these men? - Aye, lassie.
- 那小子是帕维·契科夫 - 你好
- That wee man there is Pavel Chekov. - Hello.
另一位帅哥是詹姆士·T·柯克
And that handsome bastard is James T. Kirk.
他们是我的同伴
They're my mates.
真高兴见到你 长官
It's good to see you, sir.
她要做什么 斯科特？
What is she doing, Scotty?
别伤害他们 不可以
Don't hurt them. No, don't!
是打她
Hit her!
- 你自由了 詹姆士·T - 没事了
- You're free, James T. - There we go.
斯科特
Mr. Scott.
这位新朋友是谁？
Who's your new friend here?
好个待客之道
She sure knows how to throw out a welcome mat.
- 她是洁拉 - 我不知道什么是待客之道
- This is Jaylah. - I do not know what is a welcome mat.
- 你有发现其他人吗？- 没有
- You find anybody else? - No, sir.
对不起 只有你们
I'm sorry, you're the only ones.
怎么回事？我们为什么被攻击？
What the hell happened up there, Jim? Why were we attacked?
对方想要提纳奇的文物
They were after the artifact we brought back from T eenax.
- 他们得手了吗？- 没有
- Did they get it? - No.
- 你带在身上？- 不
- Have you got it? - No.
我已经转移走了 我放在逃生舱
I had to get it off the Enterprise, put it on a shuttle.
- 你藏在逃生舱 - 是
- You hid it in a shuttle. - Yes.
也不是
And no.
这是联邦星舰富兰克林号 你相信吗？
This is the U. S. S. Franklin, sir. Can you believe it?
第一艘达到四级曲速的地球星舰
First Earth ship capable of warp 4.
2160年代早期在加加林辐射带失踪
Went missing in the Gagarin Radiation Belt in the early 2160s.
我在星舰学院读过
I remember that from the Academy.
巴尔萨泽·爱迪生舰长
Captain Balthazar Edison.
星舰最早的英雄之一
One of the first heroes of Starfleet.
他的船怎么会跑到这里？
How the hell did his ship end up here?
有很多派说法 长官
There's a lot of theories, sir.
降服于罗慕兰人 被太空绿巨手抓走
Surrendered to the Romulans. Captured by a giant green space hand.
但来到这么远的地方 一定是虫洞位移
This far out, it's got to be a wormhole displacement.
她能飞吗？
Can she fly?
她少了几个驱动器线圈
She's missing a few driver coils
少了几个电等离子系统导管
and the EPS conduits are fried,
但 洁拉用她优秀的技术
but Jaylah has done a marvelous job
让系统恢复了运作
of getting the ship's systems back online.
- 谢谢 蒙哥马利·斯科特 - 借过
- Thank you, Montgomery Scotty. - Pardon me.
契科夫 输入坐标
Mr. Chekov, can you plug in the coordinates.
用这艘船的传感器追踪舰员位置
See if you can track the crew's location from the ship's sensors.
好的 舰长
Aye, Captain.
- 他喜欢那张椅子 - 斯科特
- He likes that seat. - Mr. Scott.
- 介绍一下环境 - 我带你去看食堂
- Tour. - Yes, the mess hall.
- 洁拉 麻烦你 - 好的
- Jaylah, if you will. - Yes.
这些舰员后来怎么了？
No clue what happened to the crew, huh?
不知道 早就化为白骨了
No, sir. They'd be dead a hundred years by now.
那该不会是
Is that a...
是PX70耶
That's a PX70!
哇
Wow.
我爸爸小时候有一辆
My dad used to have one when he was a kid.
我妈说她坐在后座总是吓个半死
My mom said he'd put her on the back of it, drive her nuts.
长官
Sir.
你说这艘星舰在这里
So you're telling me this thing's been here this whole time
一直没有被发现？
and no one's ever noticed it?
她架设了影像折射器
She's rigged up image refractors.
这儿 那儿
Here. Here.
类似全像伪装的装置
So, like some sort of holographic camouflage.
是的 长官
Aye, sir.
舰长
Captain!
我拦截到微弱通讯传输
I have intercepted a weak communications transmission, sir.
是星舰的频率
It's a Starfleet frequency.
你能加强讯号吗？
Can you lock on to the signal?
可以 但要怎么过去找它们？
Yes, but how do we get to them?
我有个主意
I have an idea, sir.
可是我需要你同意
But I'm gonna need your permission.
为什么要征得我的同意？
Why would you need my permission?
因为如果搞砸了 我不想一个人扛下责任
Because if I mess it up, I don't want it to be just my fault.
麦考伊与史巴克呼叫企业号舰员
McCoy and Spock to Enterprise crew.
请回答 企业号舰员
Come in, Enterprise crew.
有人吗？
Anyone.
走吧 史巴克
Come on, Spock.
来 你可以的
Come on, you can make it.
把我留下来能 能显著增加
Leaving me behind will significantly increase
你的幸存机率 医生
your chances of survival, Doctor.
你这么说很有义气
Well, that's damn chivalrous of you,
但我办不到
but completely out of the question.
你的首要之务是找到存活的舰员
It is imperative that you locate any surviving crew.
我还以为你是关心我
And here I was thinking you cared.
我当然关心你 连纳
Of course I care, Leonard.
我对你的尊重应该显而易见
I always assumed my respect for you was clear.
多年来我们之间的对话总是
The dialogue we have had across the years has always...
别说了 史巴克
It's okay, Spock.
你不必勉强自己
You don't have to say it.
至少我不会一个人死
Well, at least I won't die alone.
我就知道事情会这样
Well, that's just typical.
来啊 混蛋
Come on, you bastards!
真高兴看到你毫发无伤
Good to see you in one piece, Doctor.
你确定？
Oh, am I?
我觉得五脏六腑都移了位
I feel like my innards have been to a barn dance!
这些老旧传送器原本只送货物
Aye, well, these old transporters were only ever used for cargo,
但我们做了一些调整
but a few modifications seem to do the trick.
我觉得最好一次传送一个人
I thought it best to beam you one at a time, though.
- 以免你们 合而为一 - 哦
- You know, in case you got spliced. - Oh.
那就再糟不过了
I couldn't imagine a worse scenario.
你能回来真好 没事吧？
Good to have you back. You all right?
我很好 倒是他受伤了
Yeah, I'm fine. He's hurt.
我的身体运作正常 舰长
I am functioning adequately, Captain.
最好是
In a pig's eye, you are!
我们发现被偷走的文物
Captain, we discovered that the stolen artifact
来自这颗行星
appears to have come from this planet.
你就别再撑了 史巴克
Damn it, Spock.
这里有医疗用品吗？
Are there any medical supplies on this thing?
跟我来
This way.
好 在这里躺着 来吧
All right. Lie down. Come on.
来
There you go.
我们要怎么度过这次危机 史巴克？
How are we gonna get out of this one, Spock?
没有船舰也没有船员 机会渺茫
We've got no ship, no crew. Not the best odds.
一如往常 吉姆
We will do what we have always done, Jim.
我们要在不可能中 寻找希望
We will find hope in the impossible.
先把你包扎好
Let's get you patched up first, okay?
不 舰长
No, Captain.
你应该专心拯救舰员
You must focus your efforts on helping the crew.
所以我才需要你在身边 史巴克
Well, that's why I need you around, Spock.
这些设备老旧到不行
These things are from the dark ages.
老骨头
Bones.
这看起来是愈合器
I'm pretty sure this is a protoplaser.
应该能止住内出血
Should stop the internal hemorrhaging.
希望行得通
At least that's my hope.
"不幸者唯一的解药便是希望"
"The miserable have no other medicine But only hope."
都快挂了 还在引用莎士比亚
Death's door and he's quoting Shakespeare.
舰长日志 星历2262.18
Captain's Log, Stardate 2262.18.
任务是例行搜查
The mission, routine investigation...
找遍了残骸都没有 一定藏在别处
我们手上只有他的舰员 克劳
如果宇宙真的浩瀚无垠
If the universe is truly endless...
两年前看似清楚的目标
What seemed so clear to me two years ago now seems,
现在却变得遥不可及
well, far away.
告诉我文物藏在哪里
You will tell me where it is!
快说
Now!
住手
Stop! Stop!
放开他 我把东西给你就是
Let him go and I will give you what you want!
丝尔 不可以
No! Syl, don't!
上尉 团结不是你们的力量
Lieutenant, unity is not your strength.
而是弱点
It is your weakness.
我们应该完全确定再行动
We should wait until we're absolutely sure.
不 我们必须马上去救他们
No, we have to get the crew back now.
契科夫已经有克劳基地的坐标 还等什么
Chekov has the coordinates that can lead us to Krall's base, so we go!
我们怎么知道我们怎么知道卡拉莱联络他的时候
With respect, sir, how do we know that Krall was at the base
克劳就在基地？
when she called him?
可我们也不知道船员在不在那儿
Even if he was, we don't know that the crew is even with him.
说不定他们都还活着
Or if they're even still alive.
契科夫 你能重新配置搜寻参数
Mr. Chekov, can you reconfigure the search parameters
来对这个公式进行补偿吗
in order to compensate for this formula?
没问题 中校 但这是什么公式？
Aye, Commander, but what is this formula?
沃卡亚的公式 契科夫
It is Vokaya, Mr. Chekov.
瓦肯特有的矿物 会发出低强度辐射
A mineral unique to Vulcan which emits low-level radiation.
我来滤除其他能量放射
I will have to filter out all other energy emissions.
这种鬼地方怎么会有瓦肯矿物？
Spock, what the hell would a Vulcan mineral be doing way out here?
你想做什么？
Where are you going with this?
乌胡拉上尉戴着我以爱意与
Lieutenant Uhura wears a Vokaya amulet
尊重之名所送的沃卡亚项链
which I presented to her as a token of my affection and respect.
你送你女朋友具放射性的首饰？
You gave your girlfriend radioactive jewelry?
它的辐射无害
The emission is harmless, Doctor.
但特征很容易识别
But its unique signature makes it very easy to identify.
你送你女友一个追踪器？
You gave your girlfriend a tracking device.
那并非我的本意
That was not my intention.
还好他不尊重我
I'm glad he doesn't respect me.
我侦测到非常微弱的沃卡亚
I am detecting a very trace amount of Vokaya.
是否与你从卡拉莱那里
Does the location match the coordinates
获得的坐标相匹配 契科夫？
you acquired from Kalara, Mr. Chekov?
是一致的
It is a match, sir.
这显示出乌胡拉上尉和其他舰员
Its presence suggests that Lieutenant Uhura and thereby the rest of the crew
都被扣留在克劳的基地
are being held at Krall's base of operation.
你能把他们传送过来吗？
Can you beam them out?
不行 舰长 那里有地表干扰
No, sir. There is some geological interference
会阻碍传送器讯号
that is blocking the transporter signal.
那么我们只能去那边一趟
Well, I guess we're gonna have to go in
用最原始的方法把他们救出来了
and break them out the old-fashioned way.
你们不能过去
You cannot go to this place.
每个过去的人 都会被他杀死
Everyone who goes there, he kills.
你 你去过 也亲眼见过？
You've... You've been there? You've seen it?
你怎么不早说 小姑娘？
Well, why didn't you say something, lassie?
因为我知道你们会叫我带路
Because I know you will ask me to take you there.
如果你们的朋友在那里 他们就会死掉
If your friends are there, then they will die,
如同我的家人一样
just like my family.
我绝对不会回去那个死地方
And I will not go back to that death place!
但你逃得出来
Aye, but if you've escaped,
代表你知道进出的路
then you can show us the way in and the way out.
不 这跟当初谈的不一样 蒙哥马利·斯科特
No! This is not the deal we made, Montgomery Scotty.
你们要去就自己去
If you choose to do this, you are on your own.
等一下
Wait.
让她走
Let her go.
她也失去了亲人
She's lost people, too, Captain.
我们的朋友在那里
Look, that's our friends out there, lassie. Right?
我们不能丢下他们
We cannae just leave them behind.
我们很需要你的帮忙
Now, we could really use your help.
只要你鼓起勇气
We just need you to be brave, is all.
我和家人在那个地方的时候
When we were in that place,
克劳会来把某个人抓走
Krall would come and take someone.
他们发出的惨叫声
There were screams.
我到现在还听得见
I can still hear them.
我们再也见不到那个人
And we would not see that person again.
下一个死的也不知道会是谁
We did not know who would be next.
我父亲计划逃走
My father planned an escape.
但我们被一个叫马纳斯的手下撞见
But we were seen by the one they call Manas.
我父亲和他打起来 让我有机会逃走
My father fought him so I could get out.
他很勇敢 但马纳斯杀了他
He was brave and Manas killed him.
你们不可能成功的
What you want is impossible.
我不这么认为
Look, maybe it's not.
我奶奶曾说过
Right. My wee granny used to say,
"一捆树枝折不断"
"Ya cannae break a stick in a bundle."
这件事牵扯的也益发严重
You're part of something bigger now, lassie.
千万别放弃
Right? Dinnae give up on that.
因为我们也不会放弃你
'Cause we'll sure as hell never give up on you.
这就是身为舰员的使命
That is what being part of a crew is all about.
你也是这么想的吗 詹姆士·T？
Is that what you believe in, James T.?
我只知道有你帮忙 我们更有机会成功
All I know is we stand a better chance with you.
挖掘的机器可以挖一个隧道 是通往坑地的
The digging machines uncovered a tunnel that goes into the crater.
我就是从那里逃出来
That's how I got out.
那我们就从那里进去
So that'll be our way in.
外遣队传送到隧道另一头
An away team will beam to the other side of the tunnel,
进入克劳的基地
follow it to Krall's base,
到建筑物里把舰员带出来
get inside the building and break out the crew.
舰长 坑洞里的人是没有办法
Uh, Captain, we cannot lock onto anyone inside the crater
被传送回来的
in order to beam them out.
我能架设脉冲信标做为增强器
Oh, I could rig up pulse beacons as pattern enhancers.
把讯号从坑洞里传出去
That'd get the signal out of the crater.
- 好吧 - 富兰克林号一次能传送多少人？
- All right. - How many people can the Franklin transport at a time?
调整过后最多20人
Uh, with a wee bit of modification, 20 max,
但我不确定能撑多久
but I'm not sure how long it would hold out.
老骨头 契科夫 洁拉
Bones, Mr. Chekov, Jaylah,
还有我是外遣队
you're with me on the away team.
斯科特 调整传送器
Mr. Scott, modify that transporter
然后尽你所能让这艘船运作
and then do everything you can to get this ship operational.
舰长 契科夫拥有的技术特长
Captain, Mr. Chekov's technical acumen
使得他与斯科特留在这星舰上更有价值
makes him more valuable aboard the Franklin with Mr. Scott.
由我来代替他合乎逻辑
It is thereby logical that I would replace him.
这样哪里合乎逻辑了？
Why is that logical, Spock?
你的伤口才刚愈合
You just got back on your feet.
乌胡拉上尉也在那里 吉姆
Lieutenant Uhura is in that facility, Jim.
我会看着他
I'll keep an eye on him.
好吧
Understood.
可是到处都是克劳的手下
But his soldiers are everywhere.
我们一定会被看见
We won't pass unseen.
我们要进行诱敌战术
What we require is a diversion.
我知道该怎么做了
I think I have an idea.
这是亚布罗讷
This is Abronath.
古住民用它当武器
It was used by the Ancient Ones as a weapon.
但他们控制不了这股致命力量
But when they could not control its deadly power,
便把它分成两半
they split it into two
发射至太空
and ejected the halves into space,
希望它永远消失
hoping it would be lost forever.
但我很感激
But I am grateful.
我花了一辈子的时间寻找它
I have spent lifetimes searching for it,
最后由你们
only to have you
替我找到了
find it for me.
这是命运的安排
The poetry of fate.
我的原生世界
The world that I was born into
跟你的很不一样 上尉
is very different from yours, Lieutenant.
我们活在痛苦和恐怖之中
We knew pain. We knew terror.
让我们变强的是斗争
Struggle made us strong.
而不是和平与团结
Not peace. Not unity.
这些都是星际联邦灌输的迷思
These are myths the Federation would have you believe.
你说得理直气壮
Those are strong words.
也可能真的这么想
You might even believe them,
但你绝对还有别的动机
but there's something else going on with you.
更深层的动机
Something underneath.
等一下
Wait.
你想对她做什么？
What are you doing with her?
你已经得到你想要的东西 放她走
You already got what you wanted! Let her go!
丝尔
Syl!
不 求求你
No, please!
放她走
Let her go!
马纳斯 时候到了
Manas, it's time.
星际联邦数百年来都在开疆拓土
The Federation has pushed the frontier for centuries.
但以后不能了
But no longer.
就从这里开始 上尉
This is where it begins, Lieutenant.
要挑战未知就要有所觉悟
This is where the frontier pushes back.
跟我来
This way.
她在哪里？
Where is she?
我必须承认 好一招声东击西
I've got to admit, that's a hell of a distraction.
你们的朋友在那里
Your friends are over there.
走吧
Come on.
他们交给我处理
你带领我们到了这一步
完成任务吧 克劳
去吧
Go!
中校 乌胡拉被带走了
Commander. Uhura, they took her.
把其他人带到安全的地方
Get the remainder of the crew to safety.
我们走 快
Come on, let's go! Move!
- 待在圆圈里 - 快点 快点
- Stay in the circle. - Come on! Hurry!
有讯号了 斯科特
I've got them, Mr. Scott!
好了 契科夫 加强讯号
Okay, Mr. Chekov, increase the signal.
一次传送20人
We're gonna grab them 20 at a time.
- 是 - 希望不会出差错
- Aye. - Let's hope this doesn't get messy.
传送
Energize!
史巴克
Spock.
你在这里做什么？
What are you doing here?
当然是来救你的
Clearly, I am here to rescue you.
我们走
Let's go.
看到你真开心 小矮子
Good to see you, wee man.
你会死在这里
就跟你父亲一样
传送器再十秒就充电完毕
Ten seconds until the transporter's recharged, Doctor.
- 等我的讯号 - 医生
- Wait for my signal. - Doctor!
听好 我们不能丢下他们离开
Damn it, man, we're not leaving without them!
我们走
Come on. Let's go. Move!
快点
Let's go! Come on!
下一个是你 舰长 快开启信标
We're ready for you next, Captain. Just turn on your beacon.
大家都传送过去了吗？
Scotty, do you have everybody?
只剩你和洁拉
Aye, sir. Everyone except you and Jaylah.
开启信标让我们抓住你
Hit the beacon and we'll grab you.
你要被丢下了
舰长 你的信标
Captain, your beacon!
- 有了 - 传送
- There it is! - Energize.
洁拉 过来
Jaylah, now!
很好
Okay...
下次别再这么做了
Let's never do that again.
我同意 詹姆士·T
I agree, James T.
你们还好吗？
You all right?
舰长 他手上的文物
Captain! This thing he has...
约克镇 他的目标是摧毁约克镇
Yorktown. He's gonna destroy Yorktown.
我的房子你拿去
You take my house
让它飞
and you make it fly.
斯科特 这艘船可以发动吗？
Scotty, can you get this thing started?
发动可以 要飞是另外一回事
Started, yes. Flying, sir, that's a different thing.
这些老船舰是在太空制造的
These old vessels, they were built in space.
起飞时不适合穿越大气
They were never supposed to take off from atmosphere.
想办法做到
Make it happen.
它们叫"星舰"是有原因的 舰长
They're called starships for a reason, Captain.
你现在才跟我讲这个？
You're telling me this now?
因为我不想让你失望 你知道的
Because I didn't want to disappoint you, you know,
以防万一你回不来
in case you didn't make it back.
- 你还真想得周到 斯科特 - 舰长
- How thoughtful, Mr. Scott. - Captain.
他开始行动了
He's launching.
攻击约克镇可能只是第一步
The attack on Yorktown may be just the beginning.
克劳拥有这种生物武器
Armed with this bio-weapon, he could rid it of all life
就可以摧毁所有生命
and use the base's advanced technology
并利用基地的先进科技 攻击其他联邦星球
to attack an untold number of Federation planets.
我们也只能硬飞了
Then we're just gonna have to get this thing flying.
引擎无法就这样发动呀
We cannae just jumpstart it, sir!
(联邦星舰富兰克林号)
好了 所有系统已就绪
Okay! All systems online.
二锂室达到70%并继续提高
Dilithium chambers at 70% and climbing.
主要支持引擎随时可以启动
Primary support engines standing by.
苏鲁
Mr. Sulu.
你应该知道 怎么驾驶吧？
You can, you know, fly this thing, right?
那还用说 长官？
You kidding me, sir?
非常好
Fantastic.
斯科特 引擎怎么样？
Scotty, how we looking?
不可能再更好了 长官
Ready as she'll ever be, sir.
这就是我想听的
That's what I like to hear. All right.
老骨头 舰员状况如何？
Bones, where are we with the crew?
要是有可以用的医疗室就好了
I could use a functioning med-bay,
不过大家已经各就各位
but otherwise we're secure down here.
苏鲁 我们要达到极速
Mr. Sulu, we have to achieve terminal velocity
才能让稳定器拉起舰身
in order for the stabilizers to provide lift.
你确定这个下坠高度够吗？
Are you sure this drop is high enough to do that?
到时就知道了
We'll find out.
下令吧 苏鲁
Call it, Mr. Sulu.
好的 舰长
Aye-aye, Captain.
契科夫 听我口令启动前方稳定器
Mr. Chekov, be ready to hit the forward stabilizers full on my mark.
- 四分之一脉冲 - 是
- One quarter impulse. - Aye.
二分之一脉冲 契科夫
One half impulse, Mr. Chekov.
知道了
Aye.
我们该系上安全带 快 快 快
We should belt up. Go on. Go!
慢一点 苏鲁 别让船裂成两半
Easy, Mr. Sulu. Let's not break her in half.
该启动了 苏鲁
Any time, Mr. Sulu.
(撞击距离)
就是现在 契科夫
Now, Mr. Chekov!
有一艘来路不明的船舰
IFF alert on incoming vessel.
没有在任何频率回报身分
No reply to all-frequency I.D. request.
影像放上屏幕
Visual.
红色警戒 红色警戒
Red alert! Red alert!
看看现在他们多进步了
Look how far they've come.
请立即前往指定安全区域
Please proceed to designated safety zones immediately.
我接收到
I'm picking up distress signals
从约克镇发出的全频求救讯号
from every frequency coming from Yorktown.
克劳已经发动攻击了
Krall's already started his attack.
斯科特 我们有什么武器可以用？
Mr. Scott, what kind of weapons do we have?
脉冲相位光炮和空间鱼雷
Uh, we have pulsed phase cannons and spatial torpedoes.
很好 弹药全载
Great. Lock and load.
没用的 你打败不了蜂群
It does not matter. You cannot defeat the bees.
或许可以把它们引开
Maybe, uh, maybe we lure them away.
我们要怎么帮约克镇争取时间？
How do we get Yorktown time to get people to safety?
跟蜂群比起来我们是破铜烂铁
No, we are a horse and buggy compared to those things.
光是自保都很吃力了
We're barely holding together as it is, Captain.
舰长 蜂群舰的飞行模式 是由特定几艘决定的
Captain, the flight patterns of bees are determined by individual decisions.
克劳的蜂群队形过于复杂
Krall's swarm formations are too complex not to rely
必须用统一的机灵感应控制
on some form of unified cyberpathic coordination.
- 据我推测 - 史巴克 讲结论
- I surmise that if we... - Spock! Skip to the end.
只要打乱蜂群的方向感
What he's saying is that if we disorient the swarm
就能把它们干掉
we can kick its ass!
完全正确
Precisely.
斯科特 你能把我传送到一艘蜂群舰上吗？
Scotty, can you beam me onto one of those swarm ships?
你疯了吗？
Have you gone completely mad?
- 到底行不行？- 不行
- Yes or no? - No!
可以啦
Yes!
可能吧
Maybe.
舰长 我对这些船舰内部有初步了解
Captain, my familiarity of the interior of those ships,
比你更适合进行这项外遣任务
however brief, makes me more qualified for this away mission.
史巴克 你伤还没好
Spock, you're still hurt.
她说得没错 史巴克
She's right, Spock.
我对关切表示感谢
I acknowledge and respect your concerns.
或许让一个熟悉蜂群舰
Perhaps you would feel more confident if I were accompanied by someone
和我伤势的人同行 你会比较放心
with familiarity of both the ship and my injury.
他一定会爱死你了
He's gonna love this.
你要我做什么？
You want me to do what?
- 来吧 医生 - 慢着
- Come along, Doctor. - Whoa! Wait a minute.
你这忘恩负义的绿血人
Why, you green-blooded ingrate.
一定是你出的鬼点子
This was your idea!
这是很好的点子 老骨头
It's a good idea, Bones.
下次你的腹部被管子刺穿
You know, next time you have a piece of pipe
叫水电工来救你吧
stuck in your transverse, call a plumber.
记得打乱它们的队形
Just make sure you find a way to break those things.
有状况 我会马上把你们传送回来
If it gets hairy, I'll beam you straight back.
传送
Energize.
一定会很顺利的
You're gonna do great!
该死 吉姆 我是医生 不是
Damn it, Jim, I'm a doctor, not a...
你知道我上次驾驶这种船舰 最后坠毁了吧
You do realize the last time I flew one of these things we crashed.
所以别怪我
So don't blame me if we...
撞到东西
Hit something.
史巴克呼叫富兰克林号
Spock to Franklin.
史巴克 请说
Spock, we read you.
舰长 就目前来看
Captain, from what I can ascertain,
它们的确通过共享一个神经网络链接
the ships do indeed share a cyberpathic link
相互沟通 协调行动的
which coordinates their actions.
我现在传给你们
Patching it through now.
就是这个讯号
That's what that signal was.
它们不是在干扰我们 而是互相交谈
They weren't jamming us, they were talking to each other.
怎么样可以让他们不要说话？
Well, how do we get them to stop talking?
用传送器进行电磁聚焦
What about electromagnetic focusing?
扰乱它们的网络
We could use the transporters, disrupt their network.
焦点可能会太明确
The focus might be too specific.
若我们在蜂群中植入干扰讯号
If we could plant some sort of disruptive communication signal inside the swarm,
或许就能破坏它们的协调能力
it might adversely affect their capacity to coordinate.
必须透过它们预想不到的频率
It would have to be at a frequency they will not anticipate.
我们可以引发连锁反应
We could cause a chain reaction
摧毁整个蜂群
that would wipe out the whole swarm.
那样的封闭网络可能会
Sir, a closed network like that
很容易受到特高频影响
might be susceptible to very high frequency.
特高频
VHF.
无线电 我们可以利用舰上广播 盖过它们的连结
Radio. We can broadcast something from the ship to drown out their link.
要很吵又令人分心
Something loud and distracting.
很吵又令人分心？
Loud and distracting?
我们有这个东西
I've got just the thing!
别弄坏我的音乐
Do not break my music.
才不会 我要帮你升级
Break it? You're getting an upgrade.
蜂群舰再60秒就要冲进去了
Swarm ships are 60 seconds from breaking through!
我只需要把特高频输出转到多相扫描
I've just got to reconfigure the VHF output into a multiphasic sweep.
让我来
Let me do it.
让她来
Let her do it.
你来
You do it.
这样就好了 很简单
There, see? Simple.
很好 舰长 可以广播了
All right. Captain, we're ready to broadcast.
讯号传不远 我们必须靠近一点
But the signal won't travel far. We have to get closer.
- 多靠近？- 非常近
- How close? - Very.
拦截路线 苏鲁
Intercept course, Mr. Sulu.
到蜂群中间
Put us right in the middle of that thing.
遵命 长官
Yes, sir.
我的老朋友
My old friend.
蜂群舰掉头了
The swarm ships are doubling back!
它们正在形成一波攻击
They are forming an attack wave, sir.
吸引到它们的注意了
I think we got their attention.
稳住 苏鲁 大家采取安全姿势
Hold steady, Mr. Sulu. Brace yourselves, everybody.
史巴克 准备离开蜂群
Spock, stand by to drop out of formation.
- 斯科特 准备好了没？- 好了 长官
- Scotty, you all cued up back there? - Aye, sir!
准备以57.7MHz广播
Ready to broadcast at 577 megahertz.
选好了吗？
Made your choice, lassie?
节拍和吼叫都有
I have the beat and shouting.
来点音乐吧
Let's make some noise.
真不错听
That's a good choice.
开快点 医生 不然 我们会被它们衰变的轨道吞噬
Faster, Doctor. We risk being consumed by their trajectorial decay.
我开车你别吵
Damn backseat driver.
- 快闪 医生 - 我有看见
- Evade, Doctor! - I see it, I see it!
那是古典乐吗？
Is that classical music?
听起来是 医生
Yes, Doctor, it would seem to be.
乌胡拉上尉 通知约克镇也用这个频率广播
Lieutenant Uhura, make sure Yorktown has the frequency to broadcast.
长官 我们取得了干扰频率
Sir, we now have the disruption frequency.
马上广播
Broadcast.
- 你们没事吧 史巴克？- 没事 舰长
- You two all right, Spock? - We are fine, Captain,
但仍有三艘船舰驶进了约克镇
but there are still three ships heading into Yorktown.
一定是克劳 跟紧他
That's got to be Krall. Keep on him, Spock.
尽全力阻止他使用武器
Do whatever it takes to stop him from using that weapon.
我的房子要垮了
My house is breaking!
我们失去了舰体装甲极性
We've lost the polarization of the hull plating!
我得把二锂室的动力重新布线
I can reroute the power from the dilithium chambers.
我需要你
I need you.
还有你 洁拉 我们走
And I need you, Jaylah. Let's go!
别跟丢了 医生
Do not lose them, Doctor.
欢迎你随时跟我换位子
You're more than welcome to switch places with me, Spock.
舰长 要一次拦截三艘船舰是不可能的
Captain, intercepting all three ships is an impossibility.
给我约克镇的示意图
Get me a schematic of Yorktown!
那里 约克镇总部
There! Yorktown headquarters!
契科夫 对中央广场进行生物扫描
Mr. Chekov, can you do a bioscan of Central Plaza?
他们正在疏散人群
They are clearing civilians.
老骨头 你们前方是中央广场
Bones, there's a city plaza coming up.
把克劳引过去
You gotta make sure Krall heads for it.
- 为什么？- 做就对了
- Why? - Just do it!
苏鲁 升上去
Sulu, get us up there.
大家坐稳了
Hold onto something!
- 干得好 老骨头 - 谢了 吉姆
- Great work, Bones. - Thanks, Jim.
现在我只需要想办法降落
Now I've just got to figure out how to land.
舰长 撞击造成舰身三处破损
Captain, I have three hull breaches from the impact.
分别在三号甲板 货物舱和引擎室
Deck 3, the cargo bay, and the engine room.
苏鲁 契科夫 检查货物舱和三号甲板
All right, Sulu, Chekov, check the cargo bay and Deck 3.
我们必须确认武器状况
We need confirmation that the weapon has been neutralized
以及克劳是否死亡
and Krall is dead!
舰长
Captain!
是克劳干的
It's Krall.
我们亲眼目睹过
We've seen him do this.
这种类似能量转移会改变他的外貌
It's some kind of energy transference. It physically changes him.
他一定还在舰上 不然早就被发现了
He must still be onboard. We would have seen him leave.
苏鲁 联络约克镇安全部 封锁舰上所有出口
Sulu, contact Yorktown security and lock down the ship.
我们走
Let's go.
开疆拓土
Push the frontier.
时间到了
It's about damn time.
- 准备好了吗？- 当然
- Are you ready? - Yeah.
好了 我们走
All right, baby, let's go.
- 时间到了 - 开疆拓土
- It's about damn time. - Push the frontier.
舰长
Captain!
- 时间到了 - 开疆拓土
- It's about damn time. - Push the frontier.
拓土
...frontier.
是他
It's him.
斯科特 进入富兰克林号的数据库
Scotty, I need you to link into the Franklin database.
查询巴尔萨泽·爱迪生
Find out what you can about Balthazar Edison.
- 富兰克林号的舰长？- 对
- The captai n of the Franklin? - Yeah.
- 他早就死了 - 不 他早死了
- Sir, he'll be long dead. - No. He's not.
我不知道为什么 但爱迪生就是克劳
I don't know how, but Edison is Krall.
有什么发现？
What'd you find?
他的纪录回溯到星际联邦成立之前
His record goes back way before the Federation even existed.
他是地球联合军事指挥部的少校
He was a major in the United Earth Military Assault
参加过多次地外战争
Command Operation. A lot of off-world combat.
他是个军人
He was a soldier.
是的 长官 战功显赫
Aye, sir. And a pretty good one.
军事指挥部解散后 他的军人生涯也画下句点
His military service came to an end when MACO was disbanded.
- 为什么？- 因为星际联邦
- Why, what happened? - The Federation, sir. Starfleet.
我们不是军事机构
We're not a military agency.
星联让他当富兰克林号舰长
They made him a captain and gave him the Franklin.
- 开启他的日志 - 好的 长官
- Scotty, bring up his logs. - Aye, sir.
- 舰长日志 - 跳到最后一篇
- Captain's Log... - Last entry.
舰长日志 我已经记不得星历了
Captain's Log... I don't remember the stardate.
所有求救讯号都没有响应
All distress calls unanswered.
所有舰员当中
Of the crew,
只有三名还活着
only three remain.
我不允许
I won't allow it!
这里的原生种族 很久之前遗弃了这颗星球
The indigenous race abandoned this planet long ago.
他们留下了精密的采矿设备
They left behind sophisticated mining equipment
和一群听人使唤的矿工
and a drone workforce.
他们拥有某种科技
They have some sort of technology
可以延续生命
that prolongs life.
我会不顾一切救我和我的舰员
I will do whatever it takes for me and my crew.
星际联邦根本不在乎我们
The Federation do not care about us.
你们可能永远不会再看到我
You'll probably never see me again.
但如果遇到了
But if you do,
我们走着瞧
be ready.
他为什么还没有使用武器？
Why has he not used his weapon yet?
他想找一个能造成最大破坏的地点
'Cause he wants to find somewhere to inflict maximum damage.
他需要一个传播系统
He needs a distribution system.
这里必须让空气流通
They have to circulate air here, right?
是的 核心有个大气调节器
Aye, sir. There's an atmospheric regulator at the core.
上尉 联络约克镇
Lieutenant, contact Yorktown.
- 在找到克劳之前别开调节器 - 是
- Make sure they shut it down until we find Krall - Yes.
他要怎么进入核心？
How would he access the core?
呃 在空间站的重力结合点
Uh, well, there's a maintenance tower
有个维修塔 那是唯一的路径
at the station's gravitational nexus. That's the only way.
斯科特 快去确保调节器是关的
Scotty, you get over there. Make sure it gets shut down!
小姑娘 跟我来
Lassie, you're with me.
大气调节器是关不掉的
Look, this thing is impossible to shut down.
这个嘛
Aye, well,
试试看就知道了
we'll see about that.
斯科特 为什么调节器还开着？
Mr. Scott, why is that thing still on?
我们正在努力 长官
We're working on it, sir,
但你该明白我要突破很多安全协议
but as you can imagine there's a lot of safety protocols
一大堆的东西 你知道的
surrounding the thing that, you know,
- 毕竟关系到所有人的性命 - 想想办法
- keeps everybody alive. - Figure something out.
小心点 舰长
Be careful, Captain.
你愈接近中心
Gravity's gonna get a bit screwy
重力的作用就越大
the closer you get to the center.
也许 我们该扫描结构图
Maybe we should scan the operational schematics,
- 看有没有后门 - 好的
- see if there's a back door. - Right.
小姑娘 我需要你盯着屏幕
Lassie, I'm gonna need your eyes.
住手
Stop!
你在那个星球发生了什么事 爱迪生？
What happened to you out there, Edison?
爱迪生
Edison.
我必须说 柯克
I have to say, Kirk,
我很想念原本的我
I've missed being me.
我们失去了自我 但生存有了目的
We lost ourselves but gained a purpose!
有一种方法可以让星系
A means to bring the galaxy
陷入斗争 使人类变强
back to the struggle that made humanity strong.
我想你低估了人类
I think you underestimate humanity.
我为人类奋战
I fought for humanity!
几百万人死于辛地与罗慕兰之战
Lost millions to the Xindi and Romulan Wars.
结果呢？
And for what?
联邦竟然要我当舰长
For the Federation to sit me in a captain's chair
跟敌人和平共存
and break bread with the enemy.
我们改变了 不这样不行
We change. We have to.
否则一辈子都得打一样的仗
Or we spend the rest of our lives fighting the same battles.
你输了
You lost!
你回不去调节器那边了
There's no way you can make it back there.
放弃吧
Give up.
跟你一样？
What, like you did?
我读了你的日志
I read your ship's log,
詹姆士·T·柯克舰长
Captain James T. Kirk.
我至少知道自己是谁
At least I know what I am.
我是一名军人
I am a soldier.
你打赢了战争 爱迪生
You won the war, Edison.
为我们带来和平
You gave us peace.
和平
Peace
不存在于我生活的世界
is not what I was born into.
斯科特
Scotty.
他正在利用重力滑流
Captain, he's using the gravitational slipstream
尝试回到中心
to carry him back to the center.
不 不
No! No!
- 那是什么？- 武器在核心了
- What's that? - The weapon's in the chamber.
舰长 我们必须马上关闭系统
Captain, we have to stop the processor now
否则约克镇所有人都会死
or everything breathing in Yorktown is dead!
你阻止不了它的
You can't stop it.
你会死
You will die.
我宁愿因为拯救生命而死
Better to die saving lives
也不要活着杀人
than to live with taking them.
这就是我生活的世界
That's what I was born into.
有个密封的施工舱口
There's a sealed construction hatch
打开通风口就能把武器排放到太空中
that will let you vent the weapon into space.
我们可以从这里解锁
Now, we can override the locks from up here,
但你必须自己开启舱口
but you will have to activate the hatch.
按个按钮就行了吧
So I just hit a button.
它不是按钮 它是个位于白色面板之下的银色拉杆
It's not a button, sir. It's a silver lever under a white panel.
- 找到了 - 总共有四个
- Got it! - And there's four of them.
开启舱口之后 马上离开
Once you've primed the hatch,you'll have to exit the chamber immediately.
如果系统开始循环而舱口是开的
If the hatch is open when the processor cycles
你会被吸到外层空间
and you're in it, you're gonna get sucked into space.
如果舱口没打开呢？
What happens if the hatch isn't open?
你会被吸到大风扇里
You're gonna get sucked into a big fan.
跟武器一起 没人能活
With the weapon, and we all die.
该死 吉姆 你会来不及
Damn it, Jim, you won't make it out in time!
通风口
The vent!
快离开 詹姆士·T
Get out of there, James T.!
斯科特 最后一个舱口打不开
Scotty, the last hatch won't open!
斯科特
Scotty!
动作快 没时间了
Work fast, Captain, time's running out!
他来不及了
He's not gonna make it.
不 不
No! No!
进入手动操控模式
Manual override engaged.
我没有你该怎么办 史巴克？
What would I do without you, Spock?
(巴尔萨泽·爱迪生 结案)
星际联邦数十年来一直当他是英雄
For decades the Federation taught that he was a hero.
只能说他的对错不是我们能评判的
I guess time will judge us all.
他只是迷失了自我
He just got lost.
你拯救了整个基地 柯克
You saved this entire base, Kirk.
数百万条性命 谢谢你
Millions of souls. Thank you.
这不只是我的功劳 从来都不是
It wasn't just me. It never is.
不用说 中将职位是你的了
Needless to say, the position of Vice Admiral is yours.
没有人比你更有资格
No one deserves it more.
中将是不上星舰的 对吧？
Vice Admirals don't fly, do they?
没错
No. They don't.
我无意冒犯 不过
Well, no offense, ma'am,
这样有什么好玩的？
but where's the fun in that?
(史巴克大使个人物品)
你根本没要求减少任务时间？
You didn't even try to get our time out here reduced?
干嘛减少？老骨头
Why would I get it reduced?
我们现在知道穿越星云的路了
Bones, we know our way through the nebula now.
想象一下会有什么新发现
Can you imagine what we'll find!
一心想置我们于死地的外星恶霸？
Alien despots hell-bent on killing us?
致命的太空病毒和细菌？
Deadly space-borne viruses and bacteria?
无法理解的宇宙异常现象
Incomprehensible cosmic anomalies that could
让我们一瞬间灰飞烟灭？
wipe us out in an instant!
一定会很好玩
It's gonna be so much fun.
我们要去哪？
By the way, where are we going?
不是要去喝一杯吗？
I thought we were gonna get a drink.
我知道你要我保持低调 不过
I know you told me to keep it under wraps, but, uh...
生日快乐
Happy Birthday!
敏感先生？
Mr. Sensitive?
- 来 给你 - 谢了 斯科特
- There you go, laddie. - Thanks, Scotty.
各位 我们举杯敬詹姆士·T·柯克舰长
Everybody, raise a glass to Captain James T. Kirk.
- 柯克舰长 - 谢谢大家
- Captain Kirk! - Thanks, everybody.
- 敬企业号 - 敬企业号
- To the Enterprise. - To the Enterprise.
还有
And
已经不在的朋友们
to absent friends.
- 敬他们 - 干杯
- Here's to that. - Cheers.
派对开始啰
All right, let's get this party started.
轮到谁了？
Whose round is it?
给我三杯罗慕兰麦芽酒
Can I get three, uh, Romulan ales for me?
我以为你要写任务报告
I thought you had to finish your mission report.
我的确要
I do.
但我认为跟你一起参加活动更有意思
But I thought it would be more pleasing to engage with you socially.
很老派的浪漫
You old romantic.
你知道苏格兰威士忌其实是
Do you know that scotch was actually invented
一名俄罗斯老太太发明的吗？
by a little old lady in Russia?
- 哦？没有多少人知道 - 失陪了
- Huh? Not many people know. - Excuse me.
你一个人喝了这么多？真厉害
Uh, did you drink all those yourself? I'm impressed.
有人说这样可以让我放松
Someone said it will take my edge off.
我还是不能放松
My edge is still not off.
这可能有帮助
All right, well, maybe this will help.
舰长做了一些安排
Captain pulled a few strings.
这是星舰学院的入学许可
That is acceptance into Starfleet Academy,
如果你想要的话
if you want it.
那里有超多规定 不要每条都遵守
They have a lot of rules. Don't listen to them all.
我一定要穿制服吗？
Will I have to wear that uniform?
恐怕是
Afraid so.
嘿 昆塞尔
Hey, Keenser.
凯文 你还是不穿裤子啊
Kevin. Still not wearing pants, I see.
我听说史巴克大使的事了
I heard about Ambassador Spock.
你上次在电梯里就是想跟我讲这个？
Is that what you wanted to mention that time in the turbolift?
差不多
More or less.
我想你和派瑞丝准将的会面 进行得很顺利
I trust your meeting with Commodore Paris went well.
差不多
More or less.
你是真的很想马上出航吧？
You really want to head back out there, huh?
(联邦星舰企业号)
太空 人类的终极疆界
Space, the final frontier.
这些是星舰企业号的旅程
These are the voyages of the Starship...
它的任务是
... Enterprise. Its continuing mission...
为了探索陌生的新世界
To explore strange new worlds.
寻找新生命
To seek out new life.
和新文明
And new civilizations.
勇敢航向人类足迹从未踏至的领域
To boldly go where no one has gone before.
《星际迷航：超越星辰》
[纪念亲爱的连纳·尼莫]
[献给安东]